Mochammad Yanuar Fitroni

Sidoarjo, Jawa Timur | +62 812-3380-6275 (WhatsApp) | +62 812-4344-2480 | moch.yanuar.f@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mochyanuarfitroni | github.com/MochammadYanuarFitroni | myanuarf-profile.vercel.app/

Summary

I'm fresh graduate of Computer Science from Universitas Pembangunan Nasional Veteran Jawa Timur with a strong interest in web development, full-stack programming, and game programming. I have previously participated and successfully graduated with good grades in an independent study program as a game programmer at the ICE Institute, as well as the Bangkit program in the field of cloud computing. I'm Interested in things that smell of technology or about software development, especially in the field of game development, websites, and anything. And i'm responsible, proficient in communication, and effective in collaborating as a team on IT projects. I have experience in game development using C#, web development using PHP, JavaScript, Node.js, and MySQL.

Experience

ICE Institute - Microcredential Game Developer

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Game Programmer

- Independent study Kampus Merdeka as Game Programmer
- Studying and recognizing every component or feature within the Unity Game Engine.
- Learning programming to create games using the C# programming language and Unity Game Engine.
- Developing 3D and 2D games such as ping-pong, top-down shooter, and 2D platformer, and integrating monetization systems into the games.
- Creating an educational game about waste management with a predetermined team.

Praktek Kerja Lapangan (PKL) – DISPERINAKER Surabaya

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022

Internship – Web Programmer

- Internship at DISPERINAKER Surabaya as Web Programmer
- Creating a website dashboard for analyzing training and certification data from DISPERINAKER by implementing data scraping from the DISPERINAKER website.
- Linking or consume RestAPI from Go with the Front-End using Vanilla JavaScript.
- Connecting the map for analyzing the distribution of training and certification participants and registrants from Tableau with the web Front-End.

Bangkit Academy 2023 – Cloud Computing Learning Path

Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

- **Cloud Computing**
 - Independent study Kampus Merdeka as Cloud Computing in Bangkit Academy 2023
 - Studying about Cloud Computing with Google Cloud, JavaScript, and Back-End RestAPI.
 - Developing a Back-End web service using Node.js and deploying it on Google Cloud.
 - Creating a RestAPI using Node.js deployed on Google Cloud for an application translating Sundanese scripts as part of the capstone project.

Education

Universitas Pembangunan Nasional Veteran Jawa Timur

Aug 2019 - Jan 2024

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics | GPA 3.90 / 4.00

- Final project titled "Pengembangan Game Edukasi Mengenai Sejarah Peroberkan Bendera Belanda pada Hotel Yamato di Surabaya".
- Internship project titled "IImplementasi Scrapping pada Data Pelatihan dan Sertifikasi Web Disperinaker Kota Surabaya untuk Dasboard Analisis".
- Served as the organizing committee for the "Pemilu Umum Raya Informatika UPN Veteran Jawa Timur 2021" as the head of the equipment division, responsible for preparing all necessary supplies.

 Published journals titled "Pembuatan Game Edukasi 'Garbage Sorter' Berbasis Android Untuk Mengenal Jenis-Jenis Sampah Menggunakan Unity" and "Pembuatan Game Edukasi Bernarasi Sejarah Insiden Perobekkan Bendera Belanda Di Hotel Yamato Menggunakan Unity".

Projects

Garbage sorter

Creating an educational mobile Android game about types of waste with the aim of enabling users or the community to understand different types of waste. <u>Itch io</u>

Sistem Informasi Disperinaker Kota Surabaya

Developing a prototype to educate users about the usage of the dashboard and information management of Disperinaker Kota Surabaya. Website Github

Sertifikasi Junior Web Programming

Building a simple e-commerce website using PHP Native programming language and the Bootstrap framework. Github

Naksu - Ngajarkeun Aksara Sunda

Developing a RestAPI using Node.js deployed on Google Cloud for an application translating Sundanese scripts. Github

Skill

Hard Skill:

- JavascriptPHP
- C#
- Web developmentGame development
- MySQL

- _
 - Bootstrap

Git Version Control

Node.Js

Soft Skill

- Adaptasi
- · Kerja sama tim
- Bertanggung jawab

Language

- Indonesia
- Inggris



KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN, KEBUDAYAAN, RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR

Nomor Ijazah Nasional : 552022024000229 Peraturan Presiden Nomor 122 Tahun 2014

Dengan ini menyatakan bahwa:

MOCHAMMAD YANUAR FITRONI

NPM: 19081010036 NIK: 3515060401010001

lahir di Surabaya tanggal 4 Januari 2001 telah menyelesaikan dengan baik dan memenuhi segala syarat Pendidikan Sarjana (S1) pada Program Studi Informatika Fakultas Ilmu Komputer, oleh sebab itu kepadanya diberikan:

IJAZAH

dengan gelar akademik

Sarjana Komputer (S.Kom.)

Lulus pada tanggal 25 Januari 2024
beserta segala hak dan kewajiban yang melekat pada Ijazah dan Gelar tersebut.
Diberikan di Surabaya pada tanggal 25 Januari 2024

Dekan

Prof. Dr. Ir. Novirina Hendrasarie, M.T. NIP. 196811261994032001

Rektor

Prof. Dr. Ir. Akhmad Fauzi, M.MT, IPU. // NIP. 196511091991031002





KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN, KEBUDAYAAN, RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR

NOMOR: 552022024000229 PERPRES: 122 TAHUN 2014

TRANSKRIP

NAMA

NOMOR POKOK MAHASISWA

TEMPAT / TANGGAL LAHIR

PROGRAM PENDIDIKAN

FAKULTAS

PROGRAM STUDI

TAHUN MASUK

: MOCHAMMAD YANUAR FITRONI

: 19081010036

: SURABAYA, 4 JANUARI 2001

: SARJANA (S1)

: ILMU KOMPUTER

: INFORMATIKA

: 2019

NO.	MATA KULIAH	SKS	NILA	1:	NO.	MATA KULIAH	SK	S NIL/
1	MATEMATIKA KOMPUTASI	3	B+	:	25	JARINGAN KOMPUTER	3	Α
2	ALGORITMA	3	A	:	26	ANALISIS & DESAIN SISTEM	3	A
3	ETIKA & KOMPETENSI INFORMATIKA	3	Λ-	:	27	STRUKTUR DATA	3	A
4	BAHASA INGGRIS DASAR	2	B-	1	28	PEMROGRAMAN BERORIENTASI OBJE	3	A
5	PENDIDIKAN PANCASILA	3	В	:	29	DESAIN & ANALISIS ALGORITMA	3	B+
6	BAHASA INDONESIA	3	В	:	30	DESAIN ANTARMUKA	3	A
7	SISTEM & TEKNOLOGI INFORMASI	3	A	:	31	MACHINE LEARNING	3	A
8	ALJABAR LINIER DAN MATRIK	3	A	1	32	PEMROGRAMAN WEB	3	A
9	ORGANISASI & ARSITEKTUR KOMPUT	3	A		33	PENGOLAHAN CITRA DIGITAL	3	B+
10	BAHASA INGGRIS LANJUTAN	2	A		34	VISI KOMPUTER	3	A
11	MATEMATIKA DISKRIT	3	A-	1	35	AUDIT IT	3	A
12	PEMROGRAMAN DASAR	3	Λ	-	36	PENGENALAN POLA	3	A
13	PENDIDIKAN KEWARGANEGARAAN	3	Λ	4	37	KECERDASAN BUATAN	3	Α-
14	AGAMA ISLAM	3	Λ	:	38	DATA MINING	3	A
15	SISTEM OPERASI	3	A		39	MANAJEMEN PROYEK	3	A
16	DESAIN BASIS DATA	3	A	:	40	STUDI INDEPENDEN 4	6	A
17	PEMROGRAMAN LANJUT	3	A	1	41	STUDI INDEPENDEN 5	6	A
18	METODE NUMERIK	3	A		42	STUDI INDEPENDEN 6	6	A
19	SISTEM DIGITAL	3	A	1	43	RISET INFORMATIKA	3	A
20	STATISTIK KOMPUTASI	3	A		44	CASE BASED REASONING	3	A
21	KEWIRAUSAHAAN	3	A			Kepemimpinan	2	A
22	BELA NEGARA	3	A	1	46	KULIAH KERJA NYATA	2	A
23	IMPLEMENTASI BASIS DATA	3	A	1	47	PRAKTEK KERJA LAPANGAN	2	A
24	REKAYASA PERANGKAT LUNAK	3			48	SKRIPSI	6	A

TANGGAL, BULAN, TAHUN KELULUSAN: 25 JANUARI 2024

JUMLAH SKS = 151

I.P.KUMULATIF = 3,90

PREDIKAT

= DENGAN PUJIAN

SURABAYA, 25 JANUARI 2024

PROF. DR. 1B. NOVIRINA HENDRASARIE, M.T. NIP. 196811261994032001



KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN, KEBUDAYAAN, RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR

PIAGAM PENGHARGAAN

NOMOR: 2024020039 / UN63 / BAKPK / 2024

Rektor Universitas Pembangunan Nasional "Veteran" Jawa Timur memberikan kepada :

Nama: MOCHAMMAD YANUAR FITRONI

Nomor Pokok Mahasiswa: 19081010036

Jenjang: Strata-1

Fakultas: Ilmu Komputer

Program Studi: Informatika

Program: Sarjana

Atas prestasinya sebagai lulusan berpredikat **DENGAN PUJIAN (Cumlaude)** dengan Indeks Prestasi Kumulatif (IPK) 3.90

Rektor

Rektor

Arot Pr. Jr. Akhmad Fauzi, M.MT, IPU.

NIP. 196511091991031002



No Seri: 122959

KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN, KEBUDAYAAN, RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR UPA PUSAT BAHASA

Jl.Raya Rungkut Madya Gunung Anyar Surabaya 60294

THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT

Name : MOCHAMMAD YANUAR FITRONI

Place of Test : LANGUAGE CENTER

ID Number : 19081010036

has achieved

English Proficiency Test (EPT) Score: 453

Section 1 : Listening Comprehension

Section 2 : Structure And Written Expression : 41

Section 3 : Reading Comprehension And Vocabulary : 48

Score Benchmark : 310 - 677

S4418912993

Surabaya, Dec 07, 2023

Syifa Syarifah Alamiyah, S.Sos., M.Commun NPT.384031002991





KEMENTERIAN PENDIDIKAN,KEBUDAYAAN,RISET, DAN TEKNOLOGI UNIVERSITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR LEMBAGA PENGEMBANGAN PEMBELAJARAN DAN PENJAMINAN MUTU

Sertifikat

DIBERIKAN KEPADA:

NAMA : MOCHAMMAD YANUAR FITRONI

NPM. : **19081010036**

PROGRAM STUDI/FAKULTAS: INFORMATIKA - FIK

NOMOR SERTIFIKAT : **081.3061/UN63.9/PBN/LP3M/2020**

TELAH MENGIKUTI PELATIHAN PRAKTIKUM MATA KULIAH PENDIDIKAN BELA NEGARA UNIVESITAS PEMBANGUNAN NASIONAL "VETERAN" JAWA TIMUR SEMESTER GASAL TA. 2020/2021 SECARA ONLINE

Surabaya, 31 Desember 2020

Dr. Indrawati Yuhertiana, MM.Ak. CA. CMA.

MATERI OUTBOUND PRAKTIKUM MATA KULIAH PENDIDIKAN BELA NEGARA

NO.	MATERI	WAKTU (JAM)	TEORI (%)	PRAKTIK (%)
Α	Kegiatan Tatap Muka	(02)	(73)	(70)
1	Konsepsi dan Substansi Kesadaran Bela Negara	2	80	20
2	Kebijakan Pembinaan Kesadaran Bela Negara	2	80	20
3	Bela Negara dalam Konteks Pembangunan Nasional	2	80	20
4	Kewaspadaan Nasional	4	80	20
5	Bahaya Radikalisme dan Komunisme Gaya Baru	2	80	20
6	Bahaya Narkotika dan Obat Terlarang	2	80	20
7	Integritas Jati Diri Bangsa	2	80	20
8	Kepemimpinan Berwawasan Kebangsaan	4	60	40
9	Kewirausahaan Berwawasan Kebangsaan		60	40
10	Pemerintahan dan Kepemerintahan yang Baik, Bersih, dan Berwibawa	4	60	40
11	Nilai dan Prinsip Anti Korupsi	2	80	20
12	Peranan Mahasiswa dalam Pencegahan Korupsi	4	40	60
	·	-1		
В	Kegiatan Penguatan Internalisasi Nilai-Nilai Bela Negara			
1	Peningkatan Wawasan Kebangsaan (Upacara, Seminar, Lokakarya, Ziarah Makam Pahlawan, Kunjungan Museum)	2	80	20
2	Mengikuti Organisasi Kemasyarakatan / Kampus	2	40	60
3	Penyuluhan Nilai-Nilai Bela Negara kepada Masyarakat	4	20	80
4	Melakukan Bhakti Sosial (Donor Darah, Penghijauan, Kebersihan Lingkungan, Penanggulangan Bencana, Gerakan Anti Narkoba)	4	20	80
С	Kegiatan Outbound Bela Negara			
1	Latihan Peraturan Baris Berbaris	1	0	100
2	Kesamaptaan Jasmani	1	0	100
3	Praktik Kepemimpinan	1	0	100
4	Praktik Pengembangan Kreatifitas	1	0	100
5	Praktik Kerjasama Tim	1	0	100
6	Praktik Teknik Berkomunikasi	1	0	100
	JUMLAH	50		



Sertifikat





DENGAN BANGGA DIBERIKAN KEPADA

Mochammad Yanuar Fitroni

ATAS PARTISIPASINYA SEBAGAI

Panitia

Dalam kegiatan Pemilu Raya Program Studi Informatika Dengan Tema "Nafas Baru HIMATIFA" yang diselenggarakan pada 1 Maret 2021

Ketua Program Studi Informatika UPN "Veteran" Jawa Timur

Budi Nugrohe, S.Kom, M.Kom NPT. 380090502051

Ketua Badan Legislatif Jurusan Prodi Informatika

UPN "Veteran" Jawa Timur

Faradella Anggi Dewi NPM. 17081010091

Ketua Pelaksana Pemilu Raya HIMATIFA 2021

Arif Widiasan Subagio NPM. 19081010065









SERTIFIKAT

GAME PROGRAMMER

diberikan kepada

Mochammad Yanuar Fitroni

telah lulus dalam Program Studi Independen Bersertifikat yang diselenggarakan oleh ICE Institute

> Sertifikat Terverifikasi September 25, 2022









BA23/GRAD/XXIII-07/C305DSX2691

Certificate of Completion

is proudly presented to

Mochammad Yanuar Fitroni

for successfully completing Bangkit, specializing in Cloud Computing.

Bangkit is a Google-led academy designed to produce high-caliber technical talent for world-class Indonesian technology companies and startups.

July 27, 2023

Dora S.

Dora Songco

Product Marketing Manager Google Indonesia











Name





STUDENT LEARNING ACHIEVEMENT

Bangkit ID : C305DSX2691

: Mochammad Yanuar Fitroni

University : Universitas Pembangunan Nasional Veteran Jawa Timur

Bangkit Completion : Full Graduate

Learning Path : Cloud Computing

Capstone Status : Finished

No	Courses/Specialization/Activities	Learning Outcomes	Hours	Score (0-100)	Score Description	
1	JavaScript Basic	By the end of the course, the student will be able to develop programs with JavaScript using Node.js and Text Editors, namely Visual Studio Code.		88	The student is skilled in developing programs with JavaScript using Node.js and Text Editors, namely Visual Studio Code.	
2	Web Programming Basic	By the end of the course, the student will be able to develop a simple website using programming code that conforms to global standards.	41	91	The student competently develops a simple website using programming code that conforms to global standards.	
3	Intro to Back-End Development using Google Cloud	By the end of the course, the student will be able to build a simple RESTful APIs independently to support the functionality of an application.		86	The student is skilled in building simple RESTful APIs independently to support functionality of an application.	
4	Google Cloud Computing Foundations	By the end of the course, the student will be able to apply basic DevOps skills.	43	91	The student is adept at applying basic DevOps skills.	
5	Google Cloud Engineer Learning Path	By the end of the course, the student will be able to comprehend and operate the essential technology of Google Cloud to become a Cloud Engineer.		91	The student is knowledgeable to grasp and operate the essential technology of Google Cloud to become a Cloud Engineer.	
6	Google Cloud Skills Boost Quests	By the end of the course, the student will be able to apply basic DevOps and machine learning dataset skills.	28	91	The student is proficient in applying basic DevOps and machine learning dataset skills.	
7	Google IT Support	By the end of the course, the student will be able to comprehend the basics of technology and modern network protocols, the overview of the cloud, practical applications, and network troubleshooting.	30	84	The student is adept at comprehending the basics of technology and modern network protocols, the overview of the cloud, practical applications, and network troubleshooting.	
8	Becoming a Google Cloud Engineer	By the end of the course, the student will be able to comprehend the cloud concepts and terminology along with the various services on the Google Cloud Platform.	42	91	The student is proficient in understanding the cloud concepts and terminology along with the various services on the Google Cloud Platform.	
9	Preparing for Associate Cloud Engineer Certification	By the end of the course, the student will be able to comprehend the exam area and learn the Google-recommended references needed to pursue the exam.	60	94	The student is adept at comprehending the exam area and studying the Google-recommended references needed to pursue the exam.	
10	Capstone / Final Project	By the end of the course, the student will be able to begin stages of a final project, namely developing an application/solution which validates their product development skills and boosts the portofolio.	200	93	The student is competent to begin stages of a final project, namely developing an application/solution which validates their product development skills and boosts the portofolio.	
11	Soft skill & Career Development	By the end of the course, the student will be able to comprehend Life Path, Growth Mindset, The Power of Feedback, Time Management, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Resilience, Project Management, Professional Communication, Networking, Digital Branding, and Interview Communication	236	93	The student thoroughly comprehends Life Path, Growth Mindset, The Power of Feedback, Time Management, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Resilience, Project Management, Professional Communication, Networking, Digital Branding, and Interview Communication	